<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cybersecurity on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/tags/cybersecurity/</link><description>Recent content in cybersecurity on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2021-2024 Kandasamy Chokkalingam</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:11:16 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kandasamyc.com/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CyberPatriot Competition</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/cyberpatriot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:11:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/cyberpatriot/</guid><description>Summary Worked with a 6 member team to demonstrate understanding in cybersecurity across different platforms Studied industry standard networking security concepts Applied networking security concepts in a competition environment</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Worked with a 6 member team to demonstrate understanding in cybersecurity across different platforms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Studied industry standard networking security concepts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Applied networking security concepts in a competition environment&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>National Cyber Scholarship Competition</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/ncsc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:11:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/ncsc/</guid><description>Summary Solved various cybersecurity, web, binary, and cryptography problems using Python, Javascript and Linux Learned about various cybersecurity techniques and topics Cyberstart This was the initial part of the competition. It was a simple CTF-esque platform with a very long running time. I solved a majority of these problems and learned a bit from the challenges they gave. One of the things I really appreciated about this platform was the provided Field Manual.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Solved various cybersecurity, web, binary, and cryptography problems using Python, Javascript and Linux&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learned about various cybersecurity techniques and topics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="cyberstart">Cyberstart&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This was the initial part of the competition. It was a simple CTF-esque platform with a very long running time. I solved a majority of these problems and learned a bit from the challenges they gave. One of the things I really appreciated about this platform was the provided Field Manual. It was a great source of information and I still have notes from it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ncs-ctf">NCS CTF&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you qualified by completing enough of Cyberstart, or through other competitions, you were invited to NCS CTF. I enjoyed competing in this CTF as well! The challenges were unique and required a fair amount of problem solving to crack. They increased in a pretty linear order and I was able to solve quite a few of them with tricks I knew beforehand and others I learned while competing. I placed high enough to become a National Cyber Scholar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="links">Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://api.badgr.io/public/assertions/T_WiBIzrR3KVHfw6_uNGDQ?identity__email=kck.choks%40gmail.com">Badgr&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>