<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughtpiece on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.me/tags/thoughtpiece/</link><description>Recent content in thoughtpiece on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2022 Kandasamy Chokkalingam</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 17:27:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kandasamyc.me/tags/thoughtpiece/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Beginning</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.me/000/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 17:27:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.me/000/</guid><description>The end of any piece is the easiest to write, I think. At least conceptually, the end has the clearest goal to accomplish: to wind up the threads and give a satisfying resolution. The beginning, on the other hand? Much harder. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent way too long putting off writing this Definitely did not mean to put this out early January post, but here we finally are, at the beginning.</description><content>&lt;p>The end of any piece is the easiest to write, I think. At least conceptually, the end has the clearest goal to accomplish: to wind up the threads and give a satisfying resolution. The beginning, on the other hand? Much harder. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent way too long putting off &lt;span class="sidenote">
&lt;label class="sidenote-label" for="writing-this">writing this&lt;/label>
&lt;input class="sidenote-checkbox" type="checkbox" id="writing-this">&lt;/input>
&lt;span class="sidenote-content">
Definitely did not mean to put this out early January
&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>
post, but here we finally are, at the beginning. So, in the interest of a writing a good beginning, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about how I got here, and what exactly here is.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="who">Who?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.kandasamyc.me/">Me&lt;/a>. This one doesn&amp;rsquo;t really need a lot of explanation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what">What?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A post on a topic that interests me. This could be anything from a &lt;a href="https://www.kandasamyc.me/tags/thoughtpice">thoughtpiece&lt;/a> to a cool solution I&amp;rsquo;ve found to a problem I&amp;rsquo;ve been having. Most posts will revolve around software development, Linux, and cybersecurity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="when">When?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hopefully every once every 3 days. This is my first time trying to do these sort of posts, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how long this lasts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="where">Where?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.kandasamyc.me/posts">Here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why">Why?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now this is bit more of a fun question. I&amp;rsquo;m doing for a few reasons: to share knowledge, to practice, and why not?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sharing-knowledge">Sharing Knowledge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I have learned &lt;em>so&lt;/em> much from sites like StackOverflow and other forums. Sometimes the only place I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to find answers are long dead forum posts from years ago or on someone&amp;rsquo;s personal website where they mention off-hand the exact information I need. They&amp;rsquo;ve been the saving grace of hours of work or research I&amp;rsquo;ve done to solve a specific bug or setup issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my goals in writing these posts and sharing this information is to give back. It&amp;rsquo;s to be there just in case someone runs into the same bug or setup issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="practice">Practice&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Probably the biggest reason I&amp;rsquo;m doing this is to work on writing things up. I was working on a project, and when it came time to share instructions and other information with other people, I found it wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy to succinctly and accurately write everything up. I remembered an anecdote I saw a screenshot of:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There was an experiment a professor did. I think it was pottery students. He did an experiment of “quality” vs “quantity”. One half of the class he told; you have to make as many pots as possible. Good pots, bad pots, whatever. The more pots you make, the higher your grade.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other half of the class were told, “you can make only one pot”. But that pot had to be perfect. The quality had to be high; the highest quality pot would get the best mark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But when it came to the grading, they noticed something weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the best quality pots were in the ‘quantity’ group.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The guys who were literally churning out pots, trying to make as many as possible, not concentrating on the quality. But every pot they made, made them better at making pots. By the end of the month (I think it was a month) - they had some pretty awesome pots coming out, because they enjoying finding all the ways and all the things they could do to make all their pots. Where as the ‘quality’ guys had spent their time reading up on pots, and technique, and researching and planning; which was all great but they’d had no further practice at actually making pots.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think this idea of repeatedly making things without worrying too much about their perfectness is a great one. That&amp;rsquo;s why I wanted to write these posts: to get practice writing things up and expressing ideas precisely and accurately.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-not">Why not?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The final reason why I wanted to write these posts is just that: because I wanted to. It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about and so I started to do it. That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how">How?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a question I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite answered yet. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a process to write these, only a rough plan. It&amp;rsquo;s something I plan to work on as I go. If I knew how to do it already, where would be the fun in trying to figure it out?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I plan to just do that. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until the next beginning,&lt;br>
ksam&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>