<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Experiences on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/</link><description>Recent content in Experiences on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2021-2024 Kandasamy Chokkalingam</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Undergraduate Research Assistant @ Software Engineering Lab @ Maryland (SEAM)</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2023-seam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2023-seam/</guid><description>Summary Developing modular decision assistance software with commercial and research applications Researching scalable, effective decision-making using LLMs for facilitation and design thinking strategies Expanding functionality through the addition of various front-end React meeting components</description><content>&lt;h1 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developing modular decision assistance software with commercial and research applications&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Researching scalable, effective decision-making using LLMs for facilitation and design thinking strategies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Expanding functionality through the addition of various front-end React meeting components&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Software Development Intern @ Verisign</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2023-verisign/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2023-verisign/</guid><description>Summary Implemented flexible and adaptable performance tests in JS with Grafana k6 Engineered continuous monitoring through a Jenkins CI/CID pipeline with Ansible and Docker Created dynamic visualizations in Grafana through exporting data into InfluxDB</description><content>&lt;h1 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Implemented flexible and adaptable performance tests in JS with Grafana k6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Engineered continuous monitoring through a Jenkins CI/CID pipeline with Ansible and Docker&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created dynamic visualizations in Grafana through exporting data into InfluxDB&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>SWE Internship @ Thomson Reuters</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2022-thomson-reuters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 19:11:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2022-thomson-reuters/</guid><description>Summary Worked at Thomson Reuters&amp;rsquo; Minneapolis office over the summer on Checkpoint, mainly with Java and Javascript Debugged a 25+ years old Java codebase to solve a critical CIAM login security issue Researched and independently producing solutions to assigned tasks in large Git/TFVC repositories Implemented custom JS protocol to migrate analytics’ data for 20,000+ users on the fly Continuing on as a part-time intern during the school year</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Worked at Thomson Reuters&amp;rsquo; Minneapolis office over the summer on Checkpoint, mainly with Java and Javascript&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Debugged a 25+ years old Java codebase to solve a critical CIAM login security issue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Researched and independently producing solutions to assigned tasks in large Git/TFVC repositories&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implemented custom JS protocol to migrate analytics’ data for 20,000+ users on the fly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continuing on as a part-time intern during the school year&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>UMD Research Internship</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2020-umd-research/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:11:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2020-umd-research/</guid><description>Summary Researched the use of reinforcement learning algorithms with Ramsey Games under Dr. William Gasarch Developed an implementation of reinforcement learning algorithms in Python with PyTorch Worked with a team to study the use of reinforcement learning in other game variants Research Over the summer of 2020, I interned under Dr. William Gasarch at the University of Maryland. Despite being a high school student, I worked with others in the REU-CAAR program on combinatorics and machine learning.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Researched the use of reinforcement learning algorithms with Ramsey Games under Dr. William Gasarch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developed an implementation of reinforcement learning algorithms in Python with PyTorch&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Worked with a team to study the use of reinforcement learning in other game variants&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="research">Research&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Over the summer of 2020, I interned under Dr. William Gasarch at the University of Maryland. Despite being a high school student, I worked with others in the REU-CAAR program on combinatorics and machine learning. I focused on Ramsey numbers and games and applying various forms of machine learning to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ramsey numbers describe the minimum size of a graph in which it cannot have a clique of a certain size where the edges are all the same color. We know the first few Ramsey numbers, but they grow in complexity very rapidly. Proofs can be convoluted and complex, but would it be possible to train machine learning models to prove them for us? Ramsey games involve two agents who color edges on a graph in turns to create a clique of a certain size. If a clique can be created, then the graph&amp;rsquo;s size is not a Ramsey number for the given clique size. Therefore, if we train machine learning models to play these games and have them play them on different graphs, we may be able to rule out certain Ramsey numbers. I focused on the first step: is it possible to train machine learning models to play these games and which type is the most efficient?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using pytorch in python, I created 4 different types of models: Monte Carlo Tree Search, Tabular Q-Learning, Deep Q-Learning, and Graph Neural Networks. Using networkx, I developed an implementation of Ramsey games and trained these models to play Ramsey games. I evaluated their performance on multiple metrics: the number of moves, win rate, mean time taken to make a move, memory used, average loss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After performing the tests, I analyzed the results. Using XeTeX, I wrote a paper describing my research, methods, results, and conclusions. I created plots and figures using matplotlib. I also created a presentation and poster, both in LaTeX, using Beamer. This was my first project using LaTeX and I really enjoyed it. Despite a bit of a steep learning curve and setup, it produced professional and clean looking results and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about formatting as much. I presented the presentation to my school in January of 2021, and my poster at ScienceMontgomery, where I was awarded an Honorable Mention in the CS category.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="links">Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.kandasamyc.com/files/umd-research-paper.pdf">Paper&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.kandasamyc.com/files/umd-research-presentation.pdf">Presentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.kandasamyc.com/files/umd-research-poster.pdf">Poster&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>FIRST Robotics Club</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/frc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:11:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/frc/</guid><description>Summary Junior Captain (2018-2019), Mechanical Lead (2019-2020), Captain (2020-2021) Led 50+ person team Developed software to control a holonomic drive base and other systems on a robot Developed a scouting data analysis platform to aid in strategy decisions and predictions Background I was a part of my high school&amp;rsquo;s FIRST Robotics Competition team for all 4 years in high school. I loved participating and was on leadership for 3 years working to make the team better.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Junior Captain (2018-2019), Mechanical Lead (2019-2020), Captain (2020-2021)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Led 50+ person team&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developed software to control a holonomic drive base and other systems on a robot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developed a scouting data analysis platform to aid in strategy decisions and predictions&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was a part of my high school&amp;rsquo;s FIRST Robotics Competition team for all 4 years in high school. I loved participating and was on leadership for 3 years working to make the team better. In addition, I drove the robot during competitions for 2 years. I participated in a variety of ways and learned so much from other people, projects, and the competition in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="activites">Activites&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="mechanical-engineering-and-design">Mechanical Engineering and Design&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In my freshman year I helped produce and manufacture parts for the robot. I used various shop tools to measure, cut, and assemble parts made of wood, metal, and polycarbonate. In my sophomore year, I helped to design a robot from scratch using Onshape, which is professional CAD software. Along with other members, I designed an accurate representation of our robot in CAD and iterated on the design as needed. To aid assembly, we produced drawings from CAD using the software, along with using CAM software to generate instructions for our CNC mill.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="software-development">Software Development&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In my senior year, I joined the programming subteam. That year, we switched to a holonomic drivebase, and, along with other members, we developed software to properly control it using an game controller. I also worked on a &lt;a href="https://www.kandasamyc.com/projects/scouting-data-ingest">project&lt;/a> to aid scouts during competition.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="development-of-outreach-programs">Development of Outreach Programs&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I also led the development of three different outreach programs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One program was targeted at local girl scout troops. Based on badge requirements, I developed a curriculum to help them get badges for robotics at different levels. I based the curriculum off othe VEX Robotics Competition parts we had and led camp sessions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another program was a week-long robotics summer camp. I helped to design the curriculum for these camps for two summers. For both summers, I put in 40-hour weeks counseling and leading these camps by managing campers and counselors, counseling campers, and making sure things ran smoothly, along with coaching other counselors before hand.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The final program was a result of the robotics summer camp. I volunteered to help mentor a group of middle school campers who wanted to establish their own VEX Robotics Competition team. For two seasons, I taught them about various aspects of robotics, helped them build their own robot, and mentored them at competitions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3d-modeling">3D Modeling&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Another project I worked on was creating renders of the CAD model of our robot. I exported the CAD model into Blender, and spent time learning how to create realistic renders of the robot. I&amp;rsquo;ve included a few of my favorite renders below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://www.kandasamyc.com/img/frc-merlin.png" alt="Merline, our 2021 robot" class="center" style="border-radius: 8px;" />
&lt;img src="https://www.kandasamyc.com/img/frc-intake.png" alt="An intake" class="center" style="border-radius: 8px;" />
&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>CyberPatriot Competition</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/cyberpatriot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:11:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/cyberpatriot/</guid><description>Summary Worked with a 6 member team to demonstrate understanding in cybersecurity across different platforms Studied industry standard networking security concepts Applied networking security concepts in a competition environment</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Worked with a 6 member team to demonstrate understanding in cybersecurity across different platforms&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Studied industry standard networking security concepts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Applied networking security concepts in a competition environment&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>National Cyber Scholarship Competition</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/ncsc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:11:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/ncsc/</guid><description>Summary Solved various cybersecurity, web, binary, and cryptography problems using Python, Javascript and Linux Learned about various cybersecurity techniques and topics Cyberstart This was the initial part of the competition. It was a simple CTF-esque platform with a very long running time. I solved a majority of these problems and learned a bit from the challenges they gave. One of the things I really appreciated about this platform was the provided Field Manual.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Solved various cybersecurity, web, binary, and cryptography problems using Python, Javascript and Linux&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learned about various cybersecurity techniques and topics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="cyberstart">Cyberstart&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This was the initial part of the competition. It was a simple CTF-esque platform with a very long running time. I solved a majority of these problems and learned a bit from the challenges they gave. One of the things I really appreciated about this platform was the provided Field Manual. It was a great source of information and I still have notes from it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ncs-ctf">NCS CTF&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you qualified by completing enough of Cyberstart, or through other competitions, you were invited to NCS CTF. I enjoyed competing in this CTF as well! The challenges were unique and required a fair amount of problem solving to crack. They increased in a pretty linear order and I was able to solve quite a few of them with tricks I knew beforehand and others I learned while competing. I placed high enough to become a National Cyber Scholar.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="links">Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://api.badgr.io/public/assertions/T_WiBIzrR3KVHfw6_uNGDQ?identity__email=kck.choks%40gmail.com">Badgr&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>