<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hackathon on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.me/tags/hackathon/</link><description>Recent content in hackathon on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2022 Kandasamy Chokkalingam</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kandasamyc.me/tags/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hop Hacks Hackathon</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.me/projects/hop-hacks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.me/projects/hop-hacks/</guid><description>Summary Collaborated with a 3 member team to create a energy usage and impact comparison tool in 36 hours Created and developed a ReactJS web app along with testing and developing a Flask backend Background I participated in the HopHacks Hackathon with two other people and we decided to make a web app to estimate users' energy consumption and compare it to global trends.
Implementation We used React to develop the web app and various libraries including React-Router to add other functionality.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Collaborated with a 3 member team to create a energy usage and impact comparison tool in 36 hours&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created and developed a ReactJS web app along with testing and developing a Flask backend&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I participated in the HopHacks Hackathon with two other people and we decided to make a web app to estimate users' energy consumption and compare it to global trends.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="implementation">Implementation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We used React to develop the web app and various libraries including React-Router to add other functionality. We then deployed it to AWS EC2 using a Flask server.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="links">Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/hophacks2021bolt/hophacks2021bolt.github.io">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>