<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Javascript on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/tags/javascript/</link><description>Recent content in Javascript on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2021-2024 Kandasamy Chokkalingam</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kandasamyc.com/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Software Development Intern @ Verisign</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2023-verisign/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2023-verisign/</guid><description>Summary Implemented flexible and adaptable performance tests in JS with Grafana k6 Engineered continuous monitoring through a Jenkins CI/CID pipeline with Ansible and Docker Created dynamic visualizations in Grafana through exporting data into InfluxDB</description><content>&lt;h1 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Implemented flexible and adaptable performance tests in JS with Grafana k6&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Engineered continuous monitoring through a Jenkins CI/CID pipeline with Ansible and Docker&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created dynamic visualizations in Grafana through exporting data into InfluxDB&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Hop Hacks Hackathon</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/projects/hop-hacks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/projects/hop-hacks/</guid><description>Summary Collaborated with a 3 member team to create a energy usage and impact comparison tool in 36 hours Created and developed a ReactJS web app along with testing and developing a Flask backend Background I participated in the HopHacks Hackathon with two other people and we decided to make a web app to estimate users&amp;rsquo; energy consumption and compare it to global trends.
Implementation We used React to develop the web app and various libraries including React-Router to add other functionality.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Collaborated with a 3 member team to create a energy usage and impact comparison tool in 36 hours&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created and developed a ReactJS web app along with testing and developing a Flask backend&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I participated in the HopHacks Hackathon with two other people and we decided to make a web app to estimate users&amp;rsquo; energy consumption and compare it to global trends.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="implementation">Implementation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We used React to develop the web app and various libraries including React-Router to add other functionality. We then deployed it to AWS EC2 using a Flask server.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="links">Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/hophacks2021bolt/hophacks2021bolt.github.io">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>SWE Internship @ Thomson Reuters</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2022-thomson-reuters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 19:11:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/experience/2022-thomson-reuters/</guid><description>Summary Worked at Thomson Reuters&amp;rsquo; Minneapolis office over the summer on Checkpoint, mainly with Java and Javascript Debugged a 25+ years old Java codebase to solve a critical CIAM login security issue Researched and independently producing solutions to assigned tasks in large Git/TFVC repositories Implemented custom JS protocol to migrate analytics’ data for 20,000+ users on the fly Continuing on as a part-time intern during the school year</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Worked at Thomson Reuters&amp;rsquo; Minneapolis office over the summer on Checkpoint, mainly with Java and Javascript&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Debugged a 25+ years old Java codebase to solve a critical CIAM login security issue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Researched and independently producing solutions to assigned tasks in large Git/TFVC repositories&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implemented custom JS protocol to migrate analytics’ data for 20,000+ users on the fly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continuing on as a part-time intern during the school year&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>