<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gatsby on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/tags/gatsby/</link><description>Recent content in Gatsby on Kandasamy Chokkalingam</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>©2021-2024 Kandasamy Chokkalingam</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:10:48 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kandasamyc.com/tags/gatsby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>C4 Website</title><link>https://www.kandasamyc.com/projects/c4-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 19:10:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.kandasamyc.com/projects/c4-website/</guid><description>Summary Developed a website using Gatsby to provide information for the C4 Club Background In high school, I was a part of the Combating Childhood Cancer Club (C4). Although we already had a website in Jekyll, I wanted to improve it by creating a more updated version using Gatsby. I wanted it to be easily maintainable and usable, even without much knowledge about web development.
Implementation I picked Gatsby for a few reasons.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Developed a website using Gatsby to provide information for the C4 Club&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In high school, I was a part of the Combating Childhood Cancer Club (C4). Although we already had a website in Jekyll, I wanted to improve it by creating a more updated version using Gatsby. I wanted it to be easily maintainable and usable, even without much knowledge about web development.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="implementation">Implementation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I picked Gatsby for a few reasons. Jekyll was a great option for the initial website, but Gatsby was more configurable and extensible. It also provided a great initial starting point to work from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using Gatsby, I extracted most of the often changed datapoints/information into either the configuration file or simple markdown files. Statistics about the organization were entered into the configuration file and rendered everywhere else from there. Other things like posts or even information were extracted the markdown files and their frontmatter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="links">Links&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://github.com/C4org/C4org.github.io">GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.c4org.github.io">Website&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>